CONTACT

• New Zealand

+64 21 132 4388

mitchell.burton@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mit chell-lawson-burton/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an experienced agile leader that looks to enhance the productivity and impact of those around me. I have been a Senior Engineer and Tech Lead of high preforming agile teams for several years. I demonstrate servant leadership and leading by example while empowering and coaching those around me. I have years of experience of working in globally distributed teams.

SKILLS

- JavaScript / TypeScript
- React
- Node.js
- C# / .NET
- Next.js
- AWS
- CI/CD
- Service Orientated Architecture
- Microservices
- API Development
- Agile
- DevEx

MITCHELL LAWSON-BURTON

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer GetSetUp

01/2022 - Present

- Developed the <u>GetSetUp Anywhere</u> product, allowing partners to embed GetSetUp video content, leading to substantial revenue impact.
- Integrated in-class user chat with Zendesk tickets, optimizing support efficiency and reducing the unit cost of classes.
- Established a remote communication charter for the team, emphasizing async communication and open communication principles.
- Built an OAuth integration between GetSetUp and Circle.so, enabling a cost-effective experiment to grow a 55+ focused community.

Principal Engineer Livestock Improvement Corporation (LIC) 11/2021 - 03/2022

- Provided key technical leadership for LIC's flagship web app: MINDA Live, a BI and farm management tool.
- Architected RESTful API services and web front end ends.

Senior Software Engineer Livestock Improvement Corporation (LIC) 02/2017 - 10/2021

- Architected RESTful API services and web front end ends.
- Responsible for the creation of the Principal Engineer role.
- Designed the interview process for engineering recruitment.

Web Developer MetOcean Solutions

07/2016 - 02/2017

- Reduced downtime and increased developer productivity.
- Introduced automated setup of production and test webservers.
- Created a deployment process.
- Created BDD contract tests for the WXTiles API.

Analyst Developer Enlighten Designs

01/2013 - 01/2016

- Became Tech Lead for an agile development team.
- Winning a client's hackathon by using Azure IOT technologies to record sensor data from the milking shed.



EDUCATION

Graduate Diploma (Philosophy) University of Waikato, 2013

Bachelor of Science with First Class Honours (Computer Science) University of Waikato, 2012